David Brixius

14417 Harcourt House Lane Pflugerville, Texas USA 78660 Phone: 512.534.5097 E-Mail: dave.brixius@gmail.com

Summary

Software engineer/web developer with 8+ years of experience. Founder of Austin Internet of Things.

Services

React, Angular, PHP, HTML, Javascript, Docker, AJAX, MySQL Database, Zend Framework, Drupal, WordPress, Joomla, LAMP stack admin, web and e-mail hosting, web design, application design, IoT.

Areas Of Expertise

Web Application Development (React, Angular, ExpressJS, PHP, MySQL, HTML5, Javascript, CSS) Responsive Web Applications Application/Network Security, MySQL Database Application Repair and Troubleshooting Web/Application Hosting, Server Admin, Business Model Development, Web Service/API Integration, IoT and Hardware Solutions. Arduino, Raspberry Pi, XBee.

Experience

Freelance Web Developer April, 2018 - Present

Freelance web developer on the following projects:

Web Development

Work with an agency using HTML, PHP, React, CSS and JavaScript to produce responsive websites to client specifications.

Arduino, XBee, API Solution

Client project involving magnetic card readers, Arduinos, Raspberry Pi, MySQL Server, and NodeJS. Working with client specifications, designed and implemented a security solution for access point entry. Designed a database schema and implemented an SQL Server on Raspberry Pi. Also designed and implemented an API back-end in Express JS. Programmed Arduinos to accept and send digital scan codes over XBee modules using the 802.15.4 Zigbee protocol. Designed and implemented web interface in React for user, access point, and permissions management.

Website Design

Work with local design agency designing responsive websites. Use HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create responsive websites for client customers.

Laravel API

Working with client specifications, designed a Postgres database schema and implemented a back-end API using Laravel for a caregiver scheduling application.

CIG Logistics - Round Rock, TX October, 2014 - April, 2018

Software Engineer Design and implementation of web-based application using React and Angular. Conversion of legacy logistics company application to current standards. Application used to track orders, incoming and on-site railcars, onsite storage, silos, outgoing trucks, and billing. Used by 60+ locations within the company across the country. 10M+ company. Application was originally created overseas, when the company was much smaller. COnverted applications to custom MVC, using the Klein router, and following MVC best practices. Workflow involved creation of Jira sprints, tasks and epics, making changes, and submitting pull requests to github. Reviewed and approved each other's pull requests. Used Vagrant for local environment. Responsible for updating shared testing environments via the Linux command line. Fluent in regex at the command line and in PHP. Application employs an extensive inheritance structure, and model classes including complex join queries to a 75 table MySQL table database. Desktop, mobile, and API versions all share the same model classes via the Klein router. Fluent with MySQL queries at the command line, and MySQL Workbench. PHPStorm is the best IDE ever! Application uses Composer. Application has a separate component written in Javascript using Node.js used on automated silos. Involved with that as needed.

Freelance Web Developer January, 2012 - October, 2014

Freelance PHP, LAMP stack, JavaScript developer. Worked for the following clients on the following projects:

Adego Marketing - Round Rock, TX (http://www.adegomarketing.com/)

Various project work with PHP and MySQL. Created responsive version of existing website.

Klayman Productions - Austin, TX

(http://www.klaymanproductions.com/) Responsive website design and coding for audio/video production company.

Port Light Technology - Grandville, MI

(http://www.portlighttechnology.com/) PHP application development for

retailer based video content advertising.

Orion, LLC - Milwaukee, WI

(http://www.orionweb.net/) Coding of Greasemonkey JavaScript user scripts.

Rice Technology, LLC - Milwaukee, WI Write socket server in Node.js, database driven web interface for water leak detection alarms. Worked with hardware and RS-232 to TCP/IP conversion boards.

Rodman Law Office - Austin, TX

(https://www.rodmanlawoffice.com/) Designed and coded custom WordPress site.

Art Investa - Perth, Western Australia (https://www.artinvesta.com/) Collaborate with another freelance web developer to address github issue tickets and resolve discovered issues using object-oriented PHP, HTML, and javascript, and CSS.

Alfred's Catering - Austin, TX

(http://alfredscatering.com/) Designed and implemented this site as a WordPress site.

King CPA Firm - Austin, TX (http://www.kingcpafirm.com/) Perform style and content changes of this Joomla site on an as-needed basis.

H2Oscore - Milwaukee, WI (https://www.h2oscore.com) Built this web application from the ground up, as a Zend Framework PHP application. Implemented GitHub VCS workflow and trained design and development team.

Sports Corner Bar and Grill - Germantown, WI (http://sportscornergt.com) Designed and implemented this site as a Drupal CMS site. Wrote custom PHP to implement dynamic content.

Clutch Restaurant - Milwaukee, WI (Closed, 2012)
Designed and implemented site as a Zend Framework
PHP site

Wisconsin Giant Pumpkin Growers - Combined Lochs, WI

(http://www.cwpg.org/) Designed and implemented this site as a Drupal CMS site.

Booth Welding and Fitting - New Ulm, MN (http://boothwf.com/) Designed and implemented this site using HTML5 Boilerplate Template. Wrote custom HTML and CSS.

1st Choice Home Inspection - Milwaukee, WI (link unavailable) Implemented this site as a 100% AJAX site, with no page reloads. Site involved a back-end database, admin and user accounts, calendar scheduling capability, and dynamically driven content

CCI Communications Group June 2011-January, 2012

Senior Web Developer Responsible for adding features to existing web web applications for GE Healthcare and Zimmer. Zimmer application was a custom database driven OOP PHP application. Worked on the English and German versions of the site. Responsible for testing of implemented changes. Also wrote code for HTML mass e-mails.

Secure Global Solutions January, 2010-May-2011

Network Security Specialist Responsible for Nagios monitoring of customer internal networks, Snort intrusion detection, e-mail content filtering, firewalls, secure SSH tunneling, and Linux network and system administration.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Computer science, minor in electrical engineering from UW-Milwaukee